Anthony Lewis Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Part II: Letters from Readers, 1957-2001 (Box II:843-940)
  - 1978
    - "M-R" miscellaneous, (5 folders)
    - Skokie, Ill.
    - "S-Z" miscellaneous, (6 folders)
    - Letters to the editor
  - 1979
    - "A" miscellaneous
    - Bureaucracy
    - "B" miscellaneous (Box II:857)
    - Cambodia
    - Carter, Jimmy
    - Crank letters
    - "C-F" miscellaneous, (4 folders)
    - "Gate"
    - "G-H" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Iran
    - Kennedy, Edward M.
    - Kissinger, Henry
    - "K" miscellaneous
    - "L" miscellaneous (Box II:858)
    - Middle East, (6 folders)
    - "M-S" miscellaneous, (6 folders)
    - "T-U" miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box II:859)
    - Vietnam
    - "V-Y" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Letters to the editor
  - 1980
    - Anderson, John Bayard, (2 folders)
    - "A-B" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Cambodia
    - "C-G" miscellaneous, (5 folders)
    - Holocaust, Jewish (1939-1945) (Box II:860)
    - "H" miscellaneous
    - Iran
    - "I-J" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Kennedy, Edward M.
    - Kissinger, Henry
    - "K-L" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Middle East, (2 folders); (3 folders) (Box II:861)
    - "M-P" miscellaneous, (4 folders)
    - Religion
    - "R-Z" miscellaneous, (7 folders)
    - Letters to the editor
  - 1981
    - "A" miscellaneous
    - Bible, Jonah (Box II:862)
    - "B-G" miscellaneous, (6 folders)
    - Haig, Alexander Meigs, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box II:863)
    - "H" miscellaneous
    - Ireland
    - "I-L" miscellaneous, (4 folders)
    - Middle East, (3 folders); (1 folder) (Box II:864)
    - "M" miscellaneous
    - Nixon, Richard M.
    - "N-Q" miscellaneous, (4 folders)
    - Religion
    - "R-S" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Tobacco
    - "T" miscellaneous
    - "U-Z" miscellaneous, (4 folders) (Box II:865)
    - Letters to the editor
  - 1982
    - "A" miscellaneous
    - Baker, Russell
    - "B-E" miscellaneous, (4 folders)
    - Falkland Islands
    - Fortas, Abe
    - "F-H" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Ireland (Box II:866)
    - "J-K" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Lyons, Louis M.
    - "L" miscellaneous
    - Middle East, (5 folders); (6 folders); (2 folders) (Box II:867, Box II:868)
    - "M" miscellaneous
    - Nazi musicologist, (2 folders)
    - "N-Q" miscellaneous, (4 folders)
    - Reagan, Ronald, "kid gloves", (2 folders)
    - "R-S" miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box II:869)
    - Times (London, England)
    - "T-Z" miscellaneous, (6 folders)
    - Letters to the editor
      - General
      - Middle East, (2 folders)
  - 1983
    - Airlines
    - "A-B" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - "C-F" miscellaneous, (4 folders) (Box II:870)
    - Grenada
    - "G-J" miscellaneous, (4 folders)
    - Kennedy, John F.
    - Kimball, Penn
    - "K-L" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Middle East, (1 folder); (3 folders) (Box II:871)
    - "M" miscellaneous
    - Nuclear
    - "N-Q" miscellaneous, (4 folders)
    - Reagan, Ronald, speech, Orlando, Fla.
    - "R" miscellaneous
    - "S-Z" miscellaneous, (7 folders) (Box II:872)
    - Letters to the editor
  - 1984
    - Abortion, (2 folders)
    - "A-B" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - "Cosi' Fan Tutte"
    - "C" miscellaneous
    - Disability (Box II:873)
    - "D-F" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Grenada
    - "G-J miscellaneous, (4 folders)
    - Khalidi, Walid, (2 folders)
    - Kimball, Penn
    - "K" miscellaneous
    - Libel letters
    - "L" miscellaneous (Box II:874)
    - Middle East, (4 folders)
    - Murdoch, Rupert
    - "M" miscellaneous
    - New Yorker
    - Nixon, Richard M.
    - Nuclear (Box II:875)
    - "N-Q" miscellaneous, (4 folders)
    - Reagan, Ronald
    - "R" miscellaneous
    - Sakharov, Andrei
    - "S-Z" miscellaneous, (8 folders)
    - Letters to the editor (Box II:876)
      - General
      - Middle East
  - 1985
    - "A-F" miscellaneous, (6 folders)
    - Gelb, Leslie
    - Germany
    - "G" miscellaneous (Box II:877)
    - Haase, Edward
    - "H-K" miscellaneous, (4 folders)
    - Libel
    - "L" miscellaneous
    - Middle East
    - "M" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - New Yorker
    - "N-O" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - "P-R" miscellaneous, (3 folders) (Box II:878)
    - Safer, Morley
    - Sharon, Ariel
    - South Africa
    - "S-W" miscellaneous, (6 folders)
    - "Z" miscellaneous (Box II:879)
    - Letters to the editor
  - 1986
    - Angola
    - "A-I" miscellaneous, (10 folders)
    - Johnson, Philip (Box II:880)
    - "J-L" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Middle East
    - "M-O" miscellaneous, (4 folders)
    - Peters, Joan, From Time Immemorial
    - Porgy and Bess
    - "P" miscellaneous
    - "R" miscellaneous (Box II:881)
    - South Africa
    - "S-V" miscellaneous, (4 folders)
    - Waldheim, Kurt
    - "W-Z" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Letters to the editor
  - 1987
    - "A" miscellaneous
    - Biter, Evelyn, "Is This America?"
    - Bork, Robert H., (2 folders) (Box II:882)
    - Buchanan, Patrick J.
    - "B-F" miscellaneous, (5 folders)
    - The Great Gatsby
    - "G" miscellaneous
    - Hart, Gary
    - "H" miscellaneous (Box II:883)
    - Iran-Contra Affair
    - "I-K" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Linder, Benjamin E.
    - "L" miscellaneous
    - MacNeil/Lehrer NewsHour
    - Marshall, George C.
    - Middle East
    - Mozambique
    - "M-Q" miscellaneous, (5 folders) (Box II:884)
    - Reagan, Ronald, (2 folders)
    - "R" miscellaneous
    - Stark (frigate) incident
    - "S-T" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - "U-Z" miscellaneous, (4 folders) (Box II:885)
    - Letters to the editor
  - 1988
    - "A-B" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Chicago, Ill., race
    - "C-I" miscellaneous, (7 folders)
    - Jackson, Jesse (Box II:886)
    - "J-L" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - MacNeil/Lehrer NewsHour
    - Middle East, (4 folders); (6 folders); (1 folder) (Box II:887, Box II:888)
    - Morgan, Elizabeth
    - "M-P" miscellaneous, (4 folders)
    - Quayle, Dan
    - "Q" miscellaneous
    - Reagan, Ronald
    - "R" miscellaneous
    - South Africa
    - "S" miscellaneous
    - Tobacco (Box II:889)
    - "T-Z" miscellaneous, (6 folders)
    - Letters to the editor
  - 1989
    - Abortion
    - "A" miscellaneous
    - Booboisie
    - "B" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Chasanow, Abraham
    - China
    - Czechoslovakia
    - "C" miscellaneous (Box II:890)
    - Drugs, (2 folders)
    - "D" miscellaneous
    - Elderly
    - "E" miscellaneous
    - Flag
    - "F-G" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - "H-L" miscellaneous, (5 folders) (Box II:891)
    - MacNeil/Lehrer NewsHour
    - Middle East, (3 folders) (Box II:892)
    - Morgan, Elizabeth
    - "M-P" miscellaneous, (5 folders)
    - "Q" miscellaneous (Box II:893)
    - Race
    - "R" miscellaneous
    - South Africa
    - Stone, I. F.
    - "S-Z" miscellaneous, (6 folders)
    - Letters to the editor
  - 1990
    - Abortion
    - Arts
    - "A-B" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Capital punishment
    - Children
    - Cold War (Box II:894)
    - Cuomo, Mario M.
    - "C-H" miscellaneous, (7 folders)
    - Iraq
    - "J-K" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - "L" miscellaneous (Box II:895)
    - Middle East, (7 folders)
    - "M" miscellaneous
    - "N-P" miscellaneous, (3 folders) (Box II:896)
    - Reagan, Ronald
    - "R-Z" miscellaneous, (8 folders)
    - Letters to the editor
  - 1991
    - "A" miscellaneous
    - "B" miscellaneous, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box II:897)
    - "C" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Duke, David
    - "D-G" miscellaneous, (5 folders)
    - "H" miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box II:898)
    - Iraq
    - "I-L" miscellaneous, (5 folders)
    - Medical insurance
    - Middle East, (2 folders)
    - "M-P" miscellaneous, (5 folders) (Box II:899)
    - Race
    - "R-T" miscellaneous, (6 folders)
    - "U-W" miscellaneous, (4 folders) (Box II:900)
    - Yugoslavia, (2 folders)
    - "Z" miscellaneous
    - Letters to the editor, (3 folders)
  - 1992
    - "A" miscellaneous
    - Brown, Jerry (Box II:901)
    - "B" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Capital punishment
    - "C-D" miscellaneous, (5 folders)
    - "E-G" miscellaneous, (7 folders) (Box II:902)
    - "H" miscellaneous, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box II:903)
    - Ireland
    - "I" miscellaneous
    - JFK (movie), (2 folders)
    - "J-L" miscellaneous, (7 folders)
    - Middle East, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box II:904)
    - "M-O" miscellaneous, (5 folders)
    - Perot, H. Ross
    - "P" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - "Q-W" miscellaneous, (9 folders) (Box II:905)
    - Yugoslavia, (1 folder); (4 folders) (Box II:906)
    - "Y-Z" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Letters to the editor, (2 folders)
  - 1993
    - Abortion, (1 folder) (Box II:907)
    - Armenia (Republic)
    - "A" miscellaneous
    - Baird, Zöe E., (3 folders)
    - "B-C" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - "D" miscellaneous, (1 folder) (Box II:908)
    - "E-F" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Gay military personnel, military policy
    - "G-K" miscellaneous, (5 folders)
    - "L" miscellaneous (Box II:909)
    - Middle East
    - "M-S" miscellaneous, (8 folders)
    - Thomas, Clarence, Anita Hill, and David Brock
    - "T-V" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Wood, Kimba Maureen
    - "W" miscellaneous
    - Yugoslavia, (8 folders); (4 folders) (Box II:910, Box II:911)
    - "Y-Z" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Letters to the editor, (2 folders)
  - 1994
    - Abortion
    - "A" miscellaneous
    - "B-D" miscellaneous, (9 folders) (Box II:912)
    - Edelman, Peter B.
    - "E-F" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - "G-H" miscellaneous, (5 folders) (Box II:913)
    - Inman, Bobby Ray
    - "I-L" miscellaneous, (5 folders)
    - Middle East, (2 folders)
    - "M-O" miscellaneous, (5 folders) (Box II:914)
    - Politics
    - "P-Q" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Right (political and religious conservatism), (3 folders) (Box II:915)
    - "R" miscellaneous
    - Simpson, O. J.
    - "S-V" miscellaneous, (7 folders)
    - Whitewater
    - "W" miscellaneous, (1 folder) (Box II:916)
    - Yugoslavia, (8 folders); (3 folders) (Box II:917)
    - "Y-Z" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Letters to the editor, (5 folders)
  - 1995 (Box II:918)
    - "A-C" miscellaneous, (4 folders)
    - Drugs
    - "D-G" miscellaneous, (5 folders)
    - "H-L" miscellaneous, (9 folders) (Box II:919)
    - Middle East
    - "M" miscellaneous, (1 folder); (3 folders) (Box II:920)
    - "N-O" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Powell, Colin L.
    - "P-S" miscellaneous, (8 folders)
    - "T-W" miscellaneous, (5 folders) (Box II:921)
    - Yugoslavia, (6 folders)
    - "Y-Z" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Letters to the editor, (3 folders) (Box II:922)
  - 1996
    - "A-C" miscellaneous, (6 folders)
    - Drugs, (1 folder) (Box II:923)
    - "D-G" miscellaneous, (8 folders)
    - "H" miscellaneous, (1 folder); (3 folders) (Box II:924)
    - "J-L" miscellaneous, (5 folders)
    - Middle East, (2 folders)
    - "M-Q" miscellaneous, (6 folders) (Box II:925)
    - Race
    - "R" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - "S" miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box II:926)
    - "T-V" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Whitewater
    - "W" miscellaneous
    - Yugoslavia
    - "Y-Z" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Letters to the editor, (5 folders)
  - 1997 (Box II:927)
    - "A-B" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Children/Prison
    - Courts
    - "C" miscellaneous
    - Drugs
    - "D-H" miscellaneous, (7 folders)
    - Immigration, (1 folder) (Box II:928)
    - "J-L" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Middle East, (6 folders); (3 folders) (Box II:929)
    - "M-Q" miscellaneous, (6 folders)
    - Race
    - "R-U" miscellaneous, (4 folders)
    - "V-X" miscellaneous, (3 folders) (Box II:930)
    - Yugoslavia
    - "Y-Z" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Letters to the editor
  - 1998
    - "A-B" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Clinton, Bill, (2 folders)
    - "C" miscellaneous
    - Drugs
    - "D-F" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - "G-H" miscellaneous, (3 folders) (Box II:931)
    - Impeachment
    - "I-L" miscellaneous, (4 folders)
    - Middle East
    - "M-R" miscellaneous, (5 folders)
    - Starr, Kenneth, (6 folders); (1 folder) (Box II:932, Box II:933, Box II:934)
    - "S-W" miscellaneous, (5 folders)
    - Yugoslavia
    - Letters to the editor
  - 1999
    - "A-B" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Creation
    - "C-H" miscellaneous, (6 folders)
    - Immigration
    - Impeachment, (1 folder); (7 folders) (Box II:935, Box II:936)
    - "J-L" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Middle East
    - "M-V" miscellaneous, (8 folders)
    - Yugoslavia
    - "W" miscellaneous
    - Letters to the editor
  - 2000
    - "A" miscellaneous
    - Bush, George W.
    - "B-E" miscellaneous, (4 folders) (Box II:937)
    - Ford, Gerald R.
    - "F" miscellaneous
    - Gonzalez, Elian
    - "G-H" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Immigration
    - "J-K" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Lee, Wen Ho
    - "L-O" miscellaneous, (4 folders)
    - Prison
    - "P-S" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - "T-Z" miscellaneous, (6 folders) (Box II:938)
    - Letters to the editor
  - 2001
    - Ashcroft, John D.
    - "A" miscellaneous
    - Bush, George W., "The Feeling of a Coup"
    - "B" miscellaneous
    - Clinton, Bill
    - "C" miscellaneous
    - Dance
    - "D-L" miscellaneous, (8 folders)
    - Middle East, (7 folders); (1 folder) (Box II:939, Box II:940)
    - "M-O" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Pentagon Papers
    - "P-V" miscellaneous, (6 folders)
    - World
    - "W-Z" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Letters to the editor
      - General
      - Middle East
- Part II: Writings, 1944-2007 (Box II:941-951)
  Correspondence, drafts of "London weekender" articles, book drafts, notes, letters to the editor, and research material.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material and therein chronologically or alphabetically.
  - Books (Box II:941)
    - Freedom for the Thought That We Hate: A Biography of the First Amendment, 2005-2007, (5 folders); (2 folders) (Box II:942)
    - Make No Law: The Sullivan Case and the First Amendment
      - Contract, 1989-1990
      - Drafts
        - Discarded pages, circa 1991
        - Set A, circa 1991, (1 folder) (Box II:943)
        - Set B, circa 1991, (2 folders)
      - Edits by Rosemary Reeve, 1991, (2 folders) (Box II:944)
      - Fox, Joseph M., 1991-1992
      - General, 1991-2000, (4 folders)
      - Jacket, 1991
      - Notes about manuscript by Mia Lewis, 1991
      - Paperback edition, 1992-2002, (2 folders) (Box II:945)
      - Permissions, 1990-2000
      - Publicity, 1991
      - Research material and notes
        - "Ad and reaction," 1960, 1971, 1989-1990
        - Brennan, William J., 1958-1964, 1990
        - Chapter 4, "The Trial," 1960-1961, 1990
        - Chapter 15, "What It Meant," 1964-1965, 1975-1977, 1989 1990
        - Chapter 18, "The Dancing Has Stopped," 1983-1990
        - Chapter 19, "Back to the Drawing Board, "1964-1971, 1984 1990, (2 folders)
        - Chapter 20, "Envoi," 1986-1990, (2 folders) (Box II:946)
        - End notes, 1979-1990, (2 folders)
        - First Amendment, 1965, 1975-1990, (3 folders); (2 folders) (Box II:947)
        - New York Times Co. v. Sullivan, Supreme Court briefs and argument, 1962-1964, 1983-1984, (4 folders)
        - Press's role in the South, 1944, 1957-1964, 1986-1990, (2 folders)
      - Reviews, 1991-1993, (3 folders) (Box II:948)
      - Serial rights, 1992
      - Tour, 1991-1992
    - Portrait of a Decade: The Second American Revolution, 1964-1970
    - The Supreme Court and How It Works: The Story of the Gideon Case, 1957-1972, (4 folders)
    - Written Into History: Pulitzer Prize Reporting of the Twentieth Century from the New York Times, 1998-2001, (5 folders) (Box II:949)
  - Letters to the editor of London publications by others (includes a few by Lewis), 1952, 1966-1984, (3 folders)
  - "London weekender articles"
    - 1965, (2 folders)
    - 1966-1968, (14 folders) (Box II:950)
    - 1969-1973, (9 folders) (Box II:951)
- Part II: Notebooks, 1964-1999 (Box II:951-961)
  Notebooks relating to Lewis's professional activities.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - 1964 (Box II:951)
  - 1965, Jan.-1966, Feb., (3 folders) (Box II:952)
  - 1966, May-1967, May, (3 folders) (Box II:953)
  - 1967, June-1969, July, (3 folders) (Box II:954)
  - 1969, Sept.-1971, Aug., (4 folders) (Box II:955)
  - 1971, Aug.-1974, (3 folders) (Box II:956)
  - 1975-1980, (4 folders) (Box II:957)
  - 1981-1982, (3 folders) (Box II:958)
  - 1983-1989, (3 folders) (Box II:959)
  - [1980s] (Box II:960)
  - 1990-1995, (4 folders)
  - 1995-1999, (2 folders) (Box II:961)
- Part II: Miscellany, 1967-2006 (Box II:961-977)
  Appointment books and calendars, address files, family papers, notes and jottings, photographs, teaching files, telephone messages, and press credentials.
  Arranged alphabetically by topic or type of material and therein alphabetically or chronologically.
  - Address file, 1978-1984, undated, (4 folders) (Box II:961)
  - Appointment books and calendars (Box II:962)
    - 1967-1969, (3 folders)
    - 1970-1972, (3 folders) (Box II:963)
    - 1973-1974, (2 folders) (Box II:964)
    - 1975-1977, (2 folders) (Box II:965)
    - 1978-1989, (4 folders) (Box II:966)
    - 1990-1998, 2006, (4 folders) (Box II:967)
  - Family papers, 1968-1969, (2 folders)
  - Notes and jottings, 1985-1986, (2 folders) (Box II:968)
  - Photographs, 1965-1977, (14 folders)
  - Press credentials, 1968, 1981, 1991-1996
  - Teaching file (Box II:969)
    - Columbia University, Graduate School of Journalism, New York, N.Y.
      - 1983-1990, (8 folders)
    - Harvard Law School, Cambridge, Mass.
      - 1974-1975
      - 1975-1976, (1 folder) (Box II:970)
      - 1976-1979, (6 folders)
      - 1980-1981, (7 folders) (Box II:971)
      - 1982-1983, (7 folders) (Box II:972)
      - 1984, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box II:973)
      - 1985, (3 folders)
      - 1986, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box II:974)
      - 1987-1990, (8 folders)
    - John F. Kennedy School of Government, Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass., 2002, (2 folders) (Box II:975)
    - Stanford University, School of Law, Stanford, Calif., 1989-1990, (4 folders); (1 folder) (Box II:976)
    - University of California, Berkeley, Calif., 1978
    - Yale University, New Haven, Conn.
      - General, 1973-1974, (2 folders)
      - Seminars 1-5, 1974, (4 folders)
      - Seminars 6-14, 1974, (5 folders) (Box II:977)
  - Telephone messages, 1985-1986, (2 folders)
- Part II: Classified, 1968-2003 (Box II:CL1)
  Transcript of telephone call and a portion of an off-the-record talk.
  Arranged according to the series, container, and folder from which the items were removed.
  - Annual file (Box CL 1)
    - 1968
      - North Atlantic Treaty Organization, 1968 (3 of 3) (Container II:25)
    - 1993
      - Reagan, Ronald, 1982 (Container II:563)
    - 2002
      - Secrecy, 1982 (Container II:793)
    - 2006
      - Terrorism
        - Rights
          - Guantanamo Bay, 2002-2003 (2 of 3) (Container II:838)